Joe Pauker

https://joepauker1.github.io South Plainfield, NJ 07080 610-573-3124 joe.pauker@live.com

SUMMARY

I am a flexible, self-motivated student with excellent knowledge in software programming, leadership, industry, and customer service. Prior to voluntarily stepping down to pursue a career change I spent over five years as a manager where I gained extensive knowledge in customer satisfaction as well as time, project, and employee management.

EDUCATION

Kean University, Union, NJ GPA: 3.84 Expect Graduation May 2020

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science, Minor Mathematics

Triangle Tech, Bethlehem, PA GPA: 4.00 Graduated 2010

Associates Degree in Specialized Technology, Carpentry and Construction Technology

COURSE WORK

Data Structures, Computer Organization and Programming, Discrete Systems, Database Management, Computer Architecture, Assembly Language, Linear Algebra, Intro to Proofs, Data Visualization

TECHINICAL SKILLS

Java, Assembly Language, HTML, PHP, MySQL, CCS, JavaScript, C

PROJECTS

Data Visualization September 2019-Present

• Create a website using MySQL, HTML, JavaScript, and CCS that will allow the user to upload a data file (wages) and translate the data into various graphs. The project is required to implement and store data on a database.

Online Banking February 2019-May 2019

- Design a mock online banking system coded with PHP, HTML and MySQL. The Project utilized PHP and MySQL skills such as creating tables, insert, delete, and select statements
- Project Link: http://eve.kean.edu/~paukerj/CPS3740/

Database Functions and Procedures

Created a variety of functions and procedures using MySQL to search a mock database and display results and/or tables. Program displayed a
message in the event of an error or indicated that no results were found.

Online Banking Design

Object-Oriented Design, collaborative, group project to create and design an online banking system. Developed a customer proposal to
include business analysis, use cases diagrams, UML diagrams, communication diagrams, and user interfaces. An oral presentation was
completed to present the project.

EXPERIENCE

ode Samurai September 2019-Present

Volunteer Computer Science tutor, specializing in database (MySQL and PHP) and basic Java skills

Part-time Customer Service Associate, Lowe's, Piscataway, NJ

September 2017-Present

- Ensure customers have a high-level shopping experience by utilizing five years of management experience to ultimately help the company to continue to succeed.
- Trained new management to streamline the integration and transition process

Back-End Support Manager, Lowe's, Piscataway, NJ

January 2017-September 2017

- Managed 20+ employees, across 5 departments, at a \$28million store
- Ensured groups consistently maintained high performance standards by resolving customer and employee conflicts when they arose.

Department Manager, Lowe's, Piscataway, NJ

March 2013-January 2017

- Oversaw biannual, full department, floor resets for spring and winter season
- Maintained departments with weekly store updates to meet and exceed overall sales and customer service experience
- Reviewed weekly sales plans, vital stats and operational reports to oversee the overall department progress and inform associates and upper management with weekly store updates

Delivery and Receiving Associate, Lowe's, Piscataway, NJ

March 2012-March 2013

Coordinated the receiving and delivery of company product, customer service and maintenance

HONORS AND ACHEIVEMENTS

- Kean University: Dean's List: 2017 Fall | 2018 Spring, Summer and Fall | 2019 Spring
- **Triangle Tech:** High Honors: all four semesters
- Lowe's: Mid-Year Employee Excellence Award: Summer 2018
- Lowe's: Manager of the Quarter: February 2015, June 2016
- Lowe's: Excellent Employee Award: 6 times over the past 6 years